Guide to the Overbrook Press Records
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Printed Material, 1930-1967; Series IV; 10.63; (26 boxes)
  - Presses and Publishers
    - Cantina Press (Box 57, Folder 544)
    - Castle Press (Box 57, Folder 545)
    - Centaur Press (Box 57, Folder 546)
    - Chapel Press (Box 57, Folder 547)
    - Charles Whitfield Drury (Box 57, Folder 548)
    - Cherryburn Press (Box 57, Folder 549)
    - Clayton Spicer Press (Box 57, Folder 550)
    - Cobble Hill Press (Box 57, Folder 551)
    - Colorplate Engraving Company (Box 57, Folder 552)
    - Colt Press (Box 57, Folder 553)
    - Columbia University Press (Box 57, Folder 554)
    - La Companie Typographique (Box 57, Folder 555)
    - The Composing Room, Inc. (Box 57, Folder 556)
    - Crabgrass Press (Box 57, Folder 557)
    - Creative Typographers (Box 57, Folder 558)
    - Cressett Press (Box 57, Folder 559)
    - Cuala Press (Box 57, Folder 560)
    - Cueno Press, Inc. (Box 57, Folder 561)
    - Cummington Press (Box 57, Folder 562)
    - Currier & Hartford Ltd. (Box 57, Folder 563)
    - Curt Valentin (Box 57, Folder 564)
    - Curwen Press (Box 57, Folder 565)
    - David R. Godine (Box 57, Folder 566)
    - Douglas Cleverdon (Box 57, Folder 567)
    - DuBois Press (Box 57, Folder 568)
    - Eugrammia Press (Box 57, Folder 569)
    - Fleuron Limited (Box 57, Folder 570)
    - Fleuron Press (Box 57, Folder 571)
    - Florence and Ralph E. Samuel (Box 57, Folder 572)
    - Frank Rea Sloan, Jr. (Box 58, Folder 573)
    - Fraser Press (Box 58, Folder 574)
    - Frederick W. Schmidt, Inc. (Box 58, Folder 575)
    - Fritz Kredel (Box 58, Folder 576)
    - Froben Press (Box 58, Folder 577)
    - Furnival Press (Box 58, Folder 578)
    - G. Van Oest (Box 58, Folder 579)
    - Geffen, Dun & Company, William E. Rudge's Sons (Box 58, Folder 580)
    - Gehenna Press (Box 58, Folder 581)
    - Gemini Press (Box 58, Folder 582)
    - George Banta Publishing Company (Box 58, Folder 583)
    - George W. Jones (Box 58, Folder 584)
    - Golden Cockerel Press (Box 58, Folder 585)
    - Grabhorn Press (Box 58, Folder 586)
    - Gravesend Press (Box 58, Folder 587)
    - H. P. Kraus (Box 58, Folder 588)
    - Haddon Craftsmen (Box 58, Folder 589)
    - Halcyon Press (Box 58, Folder 590)
    - Harbor Press (Box 58, Folder 591)
    - Harvard University Press (Box 58, Folder 592)
    - Hazell, Watson & Viney, Ltd. (Box 59, Folder 593)
    - Henry Evans, Printmaker (Box 59, Folder 594)
    - Herbert W. Simpson, Inc. (Box 59, Folder 595)
    - Herity Press (Box 59, Folder 596)
    - Higgins-McArthur Company (Box 59, Folder 597)
    - Howard Coggeshall (Box 59, Folder 598)
    - Imprint Society (Box 59, Folder 599)
    - Interlaken Mills (Box 59, Folder 600)
    - Jakob Hegner in Hellerau bei Dresden (Box 59, Folder 601)
    - James Hendrickson (Box 59, Folder 602)
    - Johannesburg Press
    - John Henry Nash (Box 59, Folder 603)
    - Jonathan Elkus (Box 59, Folder 604)
    - Junto (Box 59, Folder 605)
    - Kingsport Press (Box 59, Folder 606)
    - L. D. Allen Press (Box 59, Folder 607)
    - L. F. White Company (Box 59, Folder 608)
    - Laboratory Press (Box 59, Folder 609)
    - Lakeside Press (Box 59, Folder 610)
    - Lakeside Press (Box 60, Folder 611-612)
    - Lanston Monotype Machine Company (Box 60, Folder 613)
    - Lasky Company (Box 60, Folder 614)
    - León Pinchon (Box 60, Folder 615)
    - Little Press of Este Es (Box 60, Folder 616)
    - Mackenzie & Harris, Inc.
    - Marble Hill Press (Box 60, Folder 617)
    - Marchbanks Press (Box 60, Folder 618)
    - Marquardt & Co. (Box 60, Folder 619)
    - Maverick Press (Box 60, Folder 620)
    - McGraw-Phillips (Box 61, Folder 621)
    - Mercurius Press (Box 61, Folder 622)
    - Meriden Gravure Company (Box 61, Folder 623-624)
    - Merrion Press (Box 61, Folder 625)
    - Merrymount Press (Box 61, Folder 626)
    - Metcalf Printing and Publishing (Box 61, Folder 627)
    - Middlebury College Press (Box 61, Folder 628)
    - Mohawk Paper Mills (Box 61, Folder 629)
    - Molehill Press (Box 61, Folder 630)
    - Morgan Press (Box 61, Folder 631)
    - Museum Books, Inc. (Box 61, Folder 632)
    - New York Public Library (Box 61, Folder 633-634)
    - Nonesuch Press (Box 62, Folder 635)
    - Norman Press (Box 62, Folder 636)
    - Oak Knoll (Box 62, Folder 637)
    - Oriole Press (Box 62, Folder 638)
    - Oxford University Press (Box 62, Folder 639-640)
    - Pear Tree Press (Box 62, Folder 641)
    - Pegasus Press (Box 62, Folder 642)
    - Peter Pauper Press (Box 62, Folder 643)
    - Philip Metzger (Box 62, Folder 644)
    - Plantin Press (Box 62, Folder 645)
    - Platen Press (Box 62, Folder 646)
    - Plimpton Press (Box 62, Folder 647)
    - Powers Private Press (Box 62, Folder 648)
    - Prairie Press (Box 62, Folder 649)
    - The Press in Rowayton (Box 62, Folder 650)
    - Press of the Bilious Bull (Box 62, Folder 651)
    - Press of the Iron Horse (Box 62, Folder 652)
    - Press of the Woolly Whale (Box 62, Folder 653)
    - Princeton University Press (Box 63, Folder 654-655)
    - Printing House of Leo Hart (Box 63, Folder 656)
    - Printing Office of Philip Reed (Box 63, Folder 657)
    - Private Press (Box 63, Folder 658)
    - Privateer Press (Box 63, Folder 659)
    - Profile Press (Box 63, Folder 660)
    - Publisher's Printing Company (Box 63, Folder 661)
    - Pynson Printers (Box 63, Folder 662-663)
    - Quixote Press (Box 63, Folder 664)
    - R. R. Donnelley & Sons Company (Box 63, Folder 665)
    - Redcoat Press (Box 63, Folder 666)
    - Ron Press (Box 63, Folder 667)
    - Rumford Press (Box 63, Folder 668)
    - Rutgers University Press (Box 63, Folder 669)
    - Rydal Press (Box 63, Folder 670)
    - Sequoia Press (Box 64, Folder 671)
    - Shakespeare Head Press (Box 64, Folder 672)
    - Société de la Gravure sur bois originale (Box 64, Folder 673)
    - Spare Moments Press (Box 64, Folder 674)
    - Spiral Press (Box 64, Folder 675)
    - St. Crispin Press and Bindery
    - St. Teresa's Press and Bindery (Box 64, Folder 676)
    - Stamperia del Santuccio (Box 64, Folder 677)
    - Stinehour Press (Box 64, Folder 678)
    - Strathmore Paper Company (Box 64, Folder 679)
    - Sumac Press (Box 64, Folder 680)
    - Syracuse University Press (Box 64, Folder 681)
    - Thistle Press (Box 64, Folder 682)
    - Trianon Press (Box 64, Folder 683)
    - Trovillion Private Press (Box 64, Folder 684)
    - Type Foundry Amsterdam, Ltd. (Box 64, Folder 685)
    - University of California Press (Box 64, Folder 686)
    - University of Michigan, William L. Clements Library (Box 64, Folder 687)
    - Uphill Press (Box 64, Folder 688)
    - Vancouver Vocational Institute, Graphic Arts Department (Box 64, Folder 689)
    - W. F. Humphrey Press, Inc. (Box 64, Folder 690)
    - Walpole Printing Office (Box 64, Folder 691)
    - Wesleyan University Press (Box 64, Folder 692)
    - Will Bates Grant (Box 64, Folder 693)
    - William Edwin Rudge (Box 64, Folder 694)
    - Windsor Press (Box 65, Folder 695)
    - Yale University (Box 65, Folder 696-698)
  - Other printed material
    - The Book Collector, 1952-1955 (Box 65, Folder 699)
    - Booksellers' catalogs, 1930s (Box 65, Folder 700)
    - Booksellers' catalogs, 1940-1961, undated (Box 66, Folder 701-703)
    - The Leaflet, 1930-1931 (Box 66, Folder 704)
    - Les Cent Bibliophiles, Annuaire, 1937-1951 (Box 66, Folder 705)
    - National Committee for a Free Europe, Anniversary of the revolution of October 1917 in Russia: balance sheet of a dictatorship: what has become of the companions of Lenin and of the pioneers of the Bolshevik Revolution?, 1952
    - Printing & Graphic Arts, 1953-1960 (Box 67, Folder 706-710)
    - Trade publications, circa 1950 (Box 67, Folder 711-713)
    - Assorted pamphlets, publications, and ephemera, circa 1930-1967 (Box 68, Folder 714-718)
    - Assorted pamphlets, publications, and ephemera, circa 1930-1967 (Box 69, Folder 719-720)
- Oversize, 4; (16 boxes) + 6 broadside folders
  - Millay, Edna St. Vincent: "Twenty sonnets," photostatic copy from Reedy's Mirror (Series I.), undated (Box 70 (Oversize), Folder 721)
  - Calendier historial, photostatic copy (Series I.), undated (Box 70 (Oversize), Folder 722)
  - Nason, Thomas W., wood engraving of gambrel-roofed house (Series II.), undated (Box 70 (Oversize), Folder 723)
  - Adverse Report of the Committee on the Judiciary on a Bill to Reorganize the Judicial Branch of the Government (Series III.), 1937 (Box 70 (Oversize), Folder 724)
  - Alfred Whitney Griswold, 1906-1963: In Memoriam (Series III.), 1963-1964 (Box 70 (Oversize), Folder 725)
  - Altschul, Charles, The Influence of England: from the American Revolution in our School Text-Books (Series III.), 1954 (Box 70 (Oversize), Folder 726)
  - Ballantine, Arthur A., Uncle Charlie & Sir William and His Court (Series III.), 1950 (Box 70 (Oversize), Folder 727)
  - California, State of California, Senate concurrent resolution no. 121: relative to congratulating and commending Lawrence Arnstein on a career of outstanding achievement in the field of public health: adopted in Senate May 15, 1957; adopted in Assembly June 4, 1957 (Series III.) (Box 70 (Oversize), Folder 728)
  - Chiang Kai-Shek, Madame, Farewell Address (Series III.), 1950 (Box 70 (Oversize), Folder 729)
  - Claudel, Paul, Paroles au Maechal: Poeme (Series III.), 1941 (Box 70 (Oversize), Folder 730)
  - Cleland, T. M., 2 Letters in Praise of Progress in the Typographic and the Social Arts Addressed to Mr. Donald S. Klopfer, President, The American Institute of Graphic Arts (Series III.), 1950 (Box 70 (Oversize), Folder 731)
  - Douglas of Illinois, Editorial from The New York Times, October 20, 1966 (Series III.) (Box 70 (Oversize), Folder 732)
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D., "Spirit of Geneva," excerpt from a speech delivered by President Eisenhower on August 24, 1955 at the annual convention of the American Bar Association Independence Hall, Philadelphia (Series III.) (Box 70 (Oversize), Folder 733)
  - France, Anatole, Affaire Crainquebille; graphite drawings by William Einstein (Series III.), 1937 (Box 71 (Oversize), Folder 734-735)
  - France, Anatole, Affaire Crainquebille; lithographs after drawings by William Einstein (Series III.), 1937 (Box 71 (Oversize), Folder 736)
  - Gordon-Taylor, Gordon, Sir., Citation Delivered by Sir Gordon Gordon-Taylor on the Occasion of the Award of the Honorary Fellowship in the Royal College of Surgeons of England to Richard Lewisohn, London, February 12, 1959 (Series III.) (Box 71 (Oversize), Folder 737)
  - Hand, Learned, Rational Inquiry and the Triumph of Wisdom: Excerpt from a Speech (Series III.), 1953-1954 (Box 71 (Oversize), Folder 738)
  - Horton, Lawrence Maccoll, Prayer of Dedication for Yacht "Stranger" Delivered by Dr. Lawrence Maccoll Horton, Sunday, August 7, 1966 (Series III.) (Box 71 (Oversize), Folder 739)
  - Kingman, Brewster, Style, Pluck & Integrity. The Griswold Legacy, an Evaluation [by] Kingman Brewster ... and the Baccalaureate Address, Yale University, June, 1958 [by] A. Whitney Griswold (Series III.) (Box 71 (Oversize), Folder 740)
  - Lerner, Max, The Battle of Detroit (Series III.), 1943 (Box 71 (Oversize), Folder 741)
  - Mill, John Stuart. On Liberty (Series III.), 1940 (Box 71 (Oversize), Folder 742)
  - Phillips, Wendell, Toussaint L'Ouverture (Series III.), 1963 (Box 71 (Oversize), Folder 743)
  - Prévost, Abbé, Histoire du Chevalier des Grieux et de Manon Lescaut (Series III.), 1958 (Box 72 (Oversize), Folder 744-747)
  - Prévost, Abbé, Histoire du Chevalier des Grieux et de Manon Lescaut (Series III.), 1958 (Box 73 (Oversize), Folder 748-752)
  - Prévost, Abbé, Histoire du Chevalier des Grieux et de Manon Lescaut (Series III.), 1958 (Box 74 (Oversize), Folder 753-754)
  - Reynolds, Quentin James, "100 Percent American!" in Broun's Nutmeg (Series III.), 1939 May 27 (Box 75 (Oversize), Folder 755)
  - Shakespeare, William, The Poems of Shakespeare... (Series III.), 1939 (Box 75 (Oversize), Folder 756-758)
  - Shakespeare, William, The Poems of Shakespeare... (Series III.), 1939 (Box 76 (Oversize), Folder 759-761)
  - Stewart, George, The Blessing of the Books: A Prayer (Series III.), 1942 (Box 77 (Oversize), Folder 762)
  - Thompson, Dorothy, To Thomas Mann (Series III.), 1937 (Box 77 (Oversize), Folder 763)
  - Vandenberg, Arthur H., The American Position (Series III.), 1948 (Box 77 (Oversize), Folder 764)
  - The Voice of a Free Press: An Editorial from the New York Times, January 5, 1956 (Series III.) (Box 77 (Oversize), Folder 765)
  - We Are For Douglas, Editorial from Chicago's American, Tuesday, October 11, 1966 (Series III.) (Box 77 (Oversize), Folder 766)
  - American Political Science Association: citations and correspondence (Series III.), 1947-1952 (Box 77 (Oversize), Folder 767)
  - Bartók Archives Exhibition: ephemera (Series III.), undated (Box 77 (Oversize), Folder 768)
  - Committee for the Marshall Plan: citation (Series III.), 1948 (Box 77 (Oversize), Folder 769)
  - Council on Foreign Relations: report and citations (Series III.), 1947-1961 (Box 77 (Oversize), Folder 770)
  - "Declaration of Independence from Bossism in the Bronx": poster for Jonathan Bingham (Series III.), undated (Box 77 (Oversize), Folder 771)
  - English-Speaking Union of the United States: citations (Series III.), 1958, 1969 (Box 77 (Oversize), Folder 772)
  - First Presbyterian Church, Stamford, Connecticut: citation to William W. Graves (Series III.), 1956 (Box 77 (Oversize), Folder 773)
  - James Graham & Sons, Tom Two Arrows, "Hunted Deer," gouache on paper (Series III.), undated (Box 77 (Oversize), Folder 774)
  - Macy, Helen: Christmas card (Series III.), undated (Box 77 (Oversize), Folder 775)
  - New York Infirmary: certificate forms and citations (Series III.), 1955, undated (Box 77 (Oversize), Folder 776)
  - New York Philharmonic: poster (Series III.), 1956, undated (Box 77 (Oversize), Folder 777)
  - Overbrook Press: sign (Series III.), [1936?] (Box 78 (Oversize), Folder 778)
  - Recording for the Blind: certificates and citations, unit charters (Series III.), 1963, undated (Box 78 (Oversize), Folder 779)
  - Smith College: certificate for Hortense Mayer Hirsch (Series III.), 1968 Oct 23 (Box 78 (Oversize), Folder 780)
  - Stamford Hospital: certificate for William F. Bernart (Series III.), circa 1952 (Box 78 (Oversize), Folder 781)
  - West Hempstead Public Library: stationary and reports (Series III.), undated (Box 78 (Oversize), Folder 782)
  - "What Is Character?" broadside (Series III.), undated (Box 78 (Oversize), Folder 783)
  - Memorial broadsides (Series III.), undated (Box 78 (Oversize), Folder 784)
  - Designs and reproduction material (Series III.), undated (Box 79 (Oversize), Folder 785-787)
  - "Freud Specimen Pages" (Series III.), undated (Box 79 (Oversize), Folder 788-789)
  - Paper samples (Series III.), undated (Box 79 (Oversize), Folder 790-791)
  - Overbrook Press exhibition signs (Series I.), undated (Box 80 (Oversize), Folder 792)
  - Donors to the King George VI Memorial Fund (Series III.), 1953 (Box 80 (Oversize), Folder 793)
  - Johnson, Lyndon Baines, An Eloquent Plea for Action, an Address by President Lyndon Baines Johnson before a Joint Session of the Congress November 27, 1963 (Series III.), circa 1963 (Box 80 (Oversize), Folder 794)
  - National Jeffersonian Democrats, Declaration of Position Unanimously Adopted by the Conference of the National Jeffersonian Democrats Held in the City of Detroit, August 1936 (Series III.) (Box 80 (Oversize), Folder 795)
  - Pindar, Some Odes of Pindar: In New English Versions (Series III.), 1942 (Box 80 (Oversize), Folder 796)
  - Reston, James B., Arthur Hays Sulzberger 1891-1968: Eulogy delivered by James B. Reston at the Memorial Service Held in Temple Emanu-El December 15, 1968 (Series III.) (Box 80 (Oversize), Folder 797-798)
  - Shakespeare, William, The Poems of Shakespeare... (Series III.), 1939 (Box 80 (Oversize), Folder 799)
  - Shepardson, Whitney H., Early History of the Council on Foreign Relations (Series III.), 1960 (Box 80 (Oversize), Folder 800)
  - Stevenson, Robert Louis, An Inland Voyage (Series III.), 1936-1940 (Box 80 (Oversize), Folder 801)
  - United States, National Resources Planning Board, "Our Freedoms, Rights and Obligations" (Series III.), 1942 (Box 80 (Oversize), Folder 802)
  - Valentine, Alan, A Modest Proposal for the Care and Use of Subversives (Series III.), 1954 (Box 80 (Oversize), Folder 803)
  - Wharton, Edith, Ethan Frome (Series III.), 1967 (Box 80 (Oversize), Folder 804)
  - Wriston, Henry M., The Voices of America: Foreign Affairs (Series III.), 1953 (Box 80 (Oversize), Folder 805)
  - James Graham and Sons, "Selections from a Dealer's Choice," catalog (Series III.), undated (Box 81 (Oversize), Folder 806)
  - New York Philharmonic: poster (Series III.), 1956, undated (Box 81 (Oversize), Folder 807-808)
  - Yale University, Pierson College (Series III.), undated (Box 81 (Oversize), Folder 809)
  - Yale University, Silliman College (Series III.), undated (Box 81 (Oversize), Folder 810)
  - Designs and reproduction material (Series III.), undated (Box 81 (Oversize), Folder 811)
  - Prévost, Abbè, Histoire du Chevalier des Grieux et de Manon Lescaut; silkscreen stencils for T. M. Cleland illustrations (Series III.), undated (Box 82 (Oversize), Folder 812)
  - Prévost, Abbè, Histoire du Chevalier des Grieux et de Manon Lescaut; silkscreen stencil for T. M. Cleland illustration, in printing frame (Series III.), undated (Box 82 (Oversize), Folder 813)
  - Miscellaneous photographs (Series III.), undated (Box 83 (Oversize), Folder 814)
  - National Committee for a Free Europe, Anniversary of the revolution of October 1917 in Russia: balance sheet of a dictatorship: what has become of the companions of Lenin and of the pioneers of the Bolshevik Revolution? (Series IV.), 1952 (Box 83 (Oversize), Folder 815)
  - Albert Schiller, posters and newspaper clippings (Series IV.) (Box 83 (Oversize), Folder 816)
  - Assorted pamphlets, publications, and ephemera (Series IV.), circa 1930-1967 (Box 83 (Oversize), Folder 817)
  - Johannesburg Press (Series IV.) (Box 84 (Oversize), Folder 818)
  - John Henry Nash (Series IV.) (Box 84 (Oversize), Folder 819)
  - Laboratory Press (Series IV.) (Box 84 (Oversize), Folder 820)
  - Limited Editions Club (Series IV.) (Box 84 (Oversize), Folder 821)
  - Mackenzie & Harris, Inc. (Series IV.) (Box 84 (Oversize), Folder 822)
  - Merrion Press (Series IV.) (Box 84 (Oversize), Folder 823)
  - Peter Pauper Press (Series IV.) (Box 84 (Oversize), Folder 824)
  - St. Crispin Press and Bindery (Series IV.) (Box 85 (Oversize), Folder 825)
  - Paper samples (Series III.), undated (Box 86 (Broadside))
  - Paper samples (Series III.), undated (Box 87 (Broadside))
  - Paper samples (Series III.), undated (Box 88 (Broadside))
  - Hersey, John, Frank Altschul and the Overbrook Press, layouts and proofs (Series I.), circa 1979 (Box 89 (Broadside))
  - Cleland, T. M. "Life in Eighteenth Century France" four prints (Series II.), undated (Box 90 (Broadside))
  - Assorted pamphlets, publications, and ephemera (Series IV.), circa 1930-1967 (Box 91 (Broadside))
- Job Jackets, undated; Series V; 1.25; 3 boxes
  This accession contains white paper envelopes used by the press to hold correspondence, photographs, notes, proofs, and other materials related to specific printing jobs for customers. Some of the envelopes are empty while others contain project-related papers. They are filed in order of job number, and each has a client and project description written on the outside of the envelope.
  - For jobs 105-129, undated (Box 92)
  - For jobs 130-159, undated (Box 93)
  - For jobs 160-170. 243, undated (Box 94)
- Photoengravings and Other Printing Blocks, Series VI
  The series holds a collection of photoengravings and printing blocks used to illustrate and decorate Overbrook Press publications. They were stored in typestand drawers in the Bibliographic Press room in the basement of Sterling Memorial Library until 2015 when they were boxed for storage and transferred to the Beinecke Library. Proof prints were made at some point in the twentieth century; a binder with those prints can be found in Box 95, and a folder of oversize proof prints is in box 112. The blocks were not grouped by project or in any other order in the drawers, or in their new cartons.
  - Proof sheets binder and printing blocks (Box 95)
  - Proof sheets (Box 95)
  - Printing blocks (Box 97)
  - Printing blocks (Box 98)
  - Printing blocks (Box 99)
  - Printing blocks (Box 100)
  - Printing blocks (Box 101)
  - Printing blocks (Box 102)
  - Printing blocks (Box 103)
  - Printing blocks (Box 104)
  - Printing blocks (Box 105)
  - Printing blocks (Box 106)
  - Printing blocks (Box 107)
  - Printing blocks (Box 108)
  - Printing blocks (Box 109)
  - Printing blocks (Box 110)
  - Printing blocks (Box 111)
  - Proof sheets folder and printing blocks (Box 112)